<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<binary>
<project>general</project>
<name>rtmultiplex</name>
<location>src.bin/tcpip/rtmultiplex</location>
<syntax>rtmultiplex --help</syntax>
<syntax>rtmultiplex [-vb] [-t <ar>timeout</ar>] [-L <ar>logname</ar>] [-T <ar>timename</ar>] [-pf <ar>portname</ar>] [-if <ar>pidname</ar>] [-lp <ar>lport</ar>] <ar>hostname</ar> <ar>rport</ar></syntax>

<option><on>--help</on><od>print the help message and exit.</od>
</option>
<option><on>--version</on><od>print the RST version number and exit.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-vb</on><od>verbose. Log information to the console.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-t <ar>timeout</ar></on><od>reset the connection if no packets are received in <ar>timeout</ar> seconds. By default, the timeout is 20 seconds.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-r <ar>resetclk</ar></on><od>attempt to restart the connection on failure after <ar>resetclk</ar> seconds. By default, the resetclk is 1 second.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-L <ar>logname</ar></on><od>log connections and information in the file <ar>logname</ar>. By default, connections are recorded in <code>log.rt</code>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-T <ar>timename</ar></on><od>log the time that the last packet was received in the file <ar>timename</ar>. By default, the time is recorded in <code>time.rt</code>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-pf <ar>portname</ar></on><od>record the port number that the server is listening for connections on in the file <ar>portname</ar>. By default, the port is recorded in <code>port.id</code>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-if <ar>pidname</ar></on><od>record the process Identifier (PID) of the server in the file <ar>pidname</ar>. By default, the PID is recorded in <code>pid.id</code>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-lp <ar>lport</ar></on><od>force the server to listen on the local port number <ar>port</ar>. By default, the server requests a port number from the Operating System.</od></option>
<option><on><ar>host</ar></on><od>hostname or IP number of the system to connect to.</od></option>
<option><on><ar>rport</ar></on><od>port numbers to connect to on the server.</od></option>
<synopsis><p>TCP/IP stream mulitplexer.</p></synopsis>
<description><p>The task acts as both server and client attaching to a remote host and relaying the data stream to the client tasks.</p>
</description>

<example>
<command>rtmultiplex port.id -lf log peanut.jhuapl.edu 1024</command>
<description>Connects to the remote host <code>peanut.jhuapl.edu</code> at port 1024. Relay data from a port allocated by the operating system. The port number is recorded in the file "<code>port.id</code>" and logs of all transactions are recorded in the file "<code>log.rt</code>".</description>
</example>

<example>
<command>rtmultiplex -l 5000 port.id -lf log peanut.jhuapl.edu 1200</command>
<description>Connects to the remote host <code>peanut.jhuapl.edu</code> at port 1200. Relay data from the port 5000. The port number is recorded in the file "<code>port.id</code>" and logs of all transactions are recorded in the file "<code>log.rt</code>".</description>
</example>

</binary>
