<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<binary>
<project>superdarn</project>
<name>fov_plot</name>
<location>src.bin/tk/plot/fov_plot</location>

<syntax>fov_plot --help</syntax>
<syntax>fov_plot [<ar>options</ar>]
</syntax>
<syntax>fov_plot -png [<ar>options</ar>]</syntax>
<syntax>fov_plot -ps [-xp <ar>xoff</ar>] [-yp <ar>yoff</ar>] [<ar>options</ar>]</syntax>
<syntax>fov_plot -ppm [<ar>options</ar>]</syntax>
<syntax>fov_plot -ppmx [<ar>options</ar>]</syntax>
<syntax>fov_plot -xml [<ar>options</ar>]</syntax>
<syntax>fov_plot -x [-display <ar>display</ar>] [-xoff <ar>xoff</ar>] [-yoff <ar>yoff</ar>] [<ar>options</ar>]</syntax>
<option><on>--help</on><od>print the help message and exit.</od>
</option>
<option><on>--version</on><od>print the RST version number and exit.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-cf <ar>cfname</ar></on><od>read command line options from the file <ar>cfname</ar>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-wdt <ar>width</ar></on><od>set the width of the plot to <ar>width</ar>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-hgt <ar>height</ar></on><od>set the height of the plot to <ar>height</ar>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-pad <ar>pad</ar></on><od>set the paddding around the edges of the plot to <ar>pad</ar>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-sf <ar>scale</ar></on><od>set the scale factor (magnification) to <ar>scale</ar>. The default scale factor is 1.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-ortho</on><od>use an orthographic projection.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-stereo</on><od>use a stereographic projection.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-gvp</on><od>use a general vertical projection.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-lat <ar>lat</ar></on><od>center the plot on the latitude given by <ar>lat</ar>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-lon <ar>lon</ar></on><od>center the plot on the longitude given by <ar>lon</ar>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-latmin <ar>latmin</ar></on><od>adjust the scale factor so that the lowest visible latitude is  <ar>latmin</ar>. Applies when the stereographic projection is used.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-mag</on><od>use magnetic coordinates.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-old_aacgm</on><od>use older AACGM rather than default AACGM-v2 for magnetic coordinates.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-rotate</on><od>rotate the plot so that the local noon is at the top of the plot.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-flip</on><od>flip the direction of the X-axis.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-square</on><od>force the use of a square bounding box around the plot.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-coast</on><od>plot coastlines.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-fcoast</on><od>plot filled coastlines.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-bnd</on><od>plot state boundaries.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-grd</on><od>plot a grid.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-tmk</on><od>plot a clock-dial grid showing the time.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-grdontop</on><od>plot the grid on top of the image.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-fov</on><od>plot the radar field of view.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-ffov</on><od>plot the filled radar field of view.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-ofov</on><od>plot the field of view of all the other radars.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-fofov</on><od>plot the filled field of view of all the other radars.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-cfov</on><od>plot the field of view of radars under construction.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-fcfov</on><od>plot the filled field of view of radars under construction.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-dot</on><od>Mark the location of the radar site with a dot.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-dotr <ar>radius</ar></on><od>set the radius of the dot used to mark the station.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-tmtick <ar>tick</ar></on><od>set the grid interval for the time clock-dial to <ar>tick</ar> hours.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-lst</on><od>use local solar time rather than local time.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-term</on><od>plot the terminator.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-fterm</on><od>plot a shaded terminator.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-tmlbl</on><od>Label the time clock-dial.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-fontname <ar>fontname</ar></on><od>plot any labels using the font <ar>fontname</ar>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-fontsize <ar>fontsize</ar></on><od>set the font size to <ar>fontsize</ar> points.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-lnewdt <ar>lnewdt</ar></on><od>set the line width to <ar>lnewdt</ar>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-bgcol <ar>aarrggbb</ar></on><od>set the background color to <ar>aarrggbb</ar>, specified as the hexadecimal value for the 32-bit alpha,red,green and blue component color.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-txtcol <ar>aarrggbb</ar></on><od>set the color of the text to <ar>aarrggbb</ar>, specified as the hexadecimal value for the 32-bit alpha,red,green and blue component color.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-grdcol <ar>aarrggbb</ar></on><od>set the color of the grid to <ar>aarrggbb</ar>, specified as the hexadecimal value for the 32-bit alpha,red,green and blue component color.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-cstcol <ar>aarrggbb</ar></on><od>set the color of the coastline to <ar>aarrggbb</ar>, specified as the hexadecimal value for the 32-bit alpha,red,green and blue component color.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-bndcol <ar>aarrggbb</ar></on><od>set the color of the state boundaries to <ar>aarrggbb</ar>, specified as the hexadecimal value for the 32-bit alpha,red,green and blue component color.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-lndcol <ar>aarrggbb</ar></on><od>set the color of the land to <ar>aarrggbb</ar>, specified as the  hexadecimal value for the 32-bit alpha,red,green and blue component color.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-seacol <ar>aarrggbb</ar></on><od>set the color of the sea to <ar>aarrggbb</ar>, specified as the  hexadecimal value for the 32-bit alpha,red,green and blue component color.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-trmcol <ar>aarrggbb</ar></on><od>set the color of the terminator outline to <ar>aarrggbb</ar>, specified as the hexadecimal value for the 32-bit alpha,red,green and blue component color.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-ftrmcol <ar>aarrggbb</ar></on><od>set the color of the filled terminator to <ar>aarrggbb</ar>, specified as the hexadecimal value for the 32-bit alpha,red,green and blue component color.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-tmkcol <ar>aarrggbb</ar></on><od>set the color of the time clock-dial to <ar>aarrggbb</ar>, specified as the hexadecimal value for the 32-bit alpha,red,green and blue component color.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-fovcol <ar>aarrggbb</ar></on><od>set the color of the field of view outline to <ar>aarrggbb</ar>, specified as the hexadecimal value for the 32-bit alpha,red,green and blue component color.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-ffovcol <ar>aarrggbb</ar></on><od>set the color of the filled field of view to <ar>aarrggbb</ar>, specified as the hexadecimal value for the 32-bit alpha,red,green and blue component color.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-ofovcol <ar>aarrggbb</ar></on><od>set the color of the field of view outline of other radars to <ar>aarrggbb</ar>, specified as the hexadecimal value for the 32-bit alpha,red,green and blue component color.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-fofovcol <ar>aarrggbb</ar></on><od>set the color of the filled field of view of other radars to <ar>aarrggbb</ar>, specified as the hexadecimal value for the 32-bit alpha,red,green and blue component color.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-cfovcol <ar>aarrggbb</ar></on><od>set the color of the field of view outline of radars under construction to <ar>aarrggbb</ar>, specified as the hexadecimal value for the 32-bit alpha,red,green and blue component color.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-fcfovcol <ar>aarrggbb</ar></on><od>set the color of the filled field of view of radars under construction to <ar>aarrggbb</ar>, specified as the hexadecimal value for the 32-bit alpha,red,green and blue component color.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-d <ar>yyyymmdd</ar></on><od>plot for the date <ar>yyyymmdd</ar>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-t <ar>hr:mn</ar></on><od>plot for the time <ar>hr:mn</ar>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-st <ar>stid...</ar></on><od>plot the fields of view for the radars listed in <ar>stid</ar> which is a comma separated list of station identifier codes.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-png</on><od>produce a Portable Network Graphics (PNG) image as the output.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-ps</on><od>produce a PostScript plot as the output.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-xp <ar>xoff</ar></on><od>set the X offset of the PostScript plot to <ar>xoff</ar>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-yp <ar>xoff</ar></on><od>set the Y offset of the PostScript plot to <ar>yoff</ar>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-ppm</on><od>produce a Portable PixMap (PPM) image as the output.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-ppmx</on><od>produce an extended Portable PixMap (PPMX) image as the output.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-xml</on><od>produce an XML image representation as the output.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-x</on><od>plot on an X-terminal.</od></option>
<option><on>-display <ar>display</ar></on><od>connect to the xterminal named <ar>display</ar>.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-xoff <ar>xoff</ar></on><od>open the window, <ar>xoff</ar> pixels from the left edge of the screen.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-yoff <ar>yoff</ar></on><od>open the window <ar>ypad</ar> pixels from the top edge of the screen.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-time</on><od>plot the date and time of the plotted field of view.</od>
</option>
<option><on>-chisham</on><od>use the Chisham virtual height model.</od>
</option>
<synopsis><p>Plot the radar fields of view.</p></synopsis>
<description><p>Plot the radar fields of view.</p>
<p>The output can be to an X terminal, XML rplot file, Portable PixMap (PPM) file, extended Portable PixMap (PPMX) file, Portable Network Graphics (PNG), or PostScript file. The default output is PostScript. The output file is written to standard output.</p>
<p>The task only plots what it is instructed to plot on the command line which means that at least some of the options must be included if the plot is to show anything.</p>
<p>The default map projection is a simple cylindrical projection, the most useful projection is the stereographic projection invoked using the "<code>-stereo</code>" option.</p>
<p>The date and time options allow a plot for a specific time to be generated this is most useful when used in conjunction with the "<code>-rotate</code>" option or the "<code>-term</code>" and "<code>-fterm</code>" options.</p>
<p>The number and complexity of the command line options makes typing them a laborious process, especially when producing multiple plots. To solve this problem, command line options can be placed in plain text file that can be parsed by the program using the " <code>-cf</code>" option. This allows the user to create a set of configuration files for producing different plots.</p> 
</description>

<example>
<command>fov_plot -grd -fov -ffov -stereo -mag -x -st kod </command>
<description> Plot a stereographic projection in magnetic coordinates of the Kodiak field of view on an X terminal. Show a grid of latitude and longitude.</description>
</example>

<example>
<command>fov_plot -ps -grd -fov -ffov -stereo -coast -st gbr &gt; gbr.ps</command>
<description>Generate a PostScript plot of the Goose Bay field of view using a stereographic projection. Show coastlines and a grid of longitude and latitude. The plot is stored in the file "<code>gbr.ps</code>".</description>
</example>

<example type="rplot">example1</example>

<example>
<command>fov_plot -grd -fov -ffov -ortho -fterm -d 20040312 -t 12:00 -fcoast -coast -ofov -fofov -st sas &gt sas.rp.xml
</command>
<description>Generate an rXML  plot of the Saskatoon field of view using an orthographic projection. Show coastlines, shade land and sea, overlay a grid of longitude and latitude. Show the fields of view of the other radars. Shade the image to show the terminator for a  time of March 12, 2004 at 12:00 UTC. The plot is stored in the file "<code>sas.rp.xml</code>".</description>
</example>

<example type="rplot">example2</example>

</binary>
